# Rae Khan . Jarvis Consulting

My name is Rae Khan, I have recently joined Jarvis as a Data Engineer and would like to introduce myself. I have earned a Bachelors of Aerospace Engineering from Ryerson University. Throughout my academic career, I became proficient at MATLAB coding and within the last several years, I have honed my software skills. I have completed courses on platforms such as Udemy and edX in topics such as VBA programming and SQL. In my previous position, I worked as a Python Instructor. I taught various students the basics of Python, such as syntax, data types, and functions. Additionally, I recently completed a Web Development Bootcamp at Lighthouse Labs gaining additional software skills such as JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. I look forward to expanding my software skillset with Jarvis.

### Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git Competent: JavaScript, Python, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, VBA

Familiar: Ruby, React, JQuery, Ajax, Express

### Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_RaeKhan

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: The purpose of this project is to monitor a cluster of servers running CentOS 7 for the Jarvis Linux Cluster Administration (LCA) Team. Data is obtained and inserted in an RDBMS database using PostgreSQL, Docker, crontab, and Bash.

## **Highlighted Projects**

Fantasy Basketball Helper App [GitHub]: Aided in the development of a mobile application that allows users to see rich basketball data for their fantasy team to make more informed decisions. Created using Javascript and HTML.

Tweeter [GitHub]: Created a simplified single page Twitter clone created using HTML, CSS, JQuery and Ajax.

**DinoDiscount** [GitHub]: Collaborated on a full stack web application designed to buy/sell items, similar to Kijiji, created using EJS, JS, HTML and CSS.

### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Participating in agile best practises working on various software projects including Linux, Bash, SQL, and Java.

Virtual Python Instructor, Geek Education (2021): Educated upwards of 25 students ages 8 - 12 individually on the basics of Python, including various topics on syntax, functions, and variables.

Lead Robotics Instructor, Institute of Robotics and Intelligent Systems (2019-2021): Enthusiastically taught approximately 30 students ages 5 - 12 over 12 weeks on various courses, including Basic Python, 3D Printing, Lego EV3 Robotics, and Lego Wedo Robotics.

### Education

Lighthouse Labs (2021 - 2021), Web Development Bootcamp Diploma, Web Development

Ryerson University (2014 - 2021), Bachelor of Aerospace Engineering, Aerospace Engineering

#### Miscellaneous

- edX Querying with T-SQL (2020)
- Udemy Excel VBA & Excel Macros (2020)
- LinkedIn Agile Software Development (2020)
- Avid reader
- Fitness enthusiast
- Photography